people chew is my least favorite noise
you know it's funny I was actually just
talking about the other day seems like
if you break down it's better for us as
humans if we did chew with our mouths
open
like we if we all were just like I don't
know that I have no idea I think it just
seems yeah so welcome to the junk our
love podcast to start things off
Spencer and I are just gonna for five
minutes make ASMR sounds into the
microphone okay I'm down with it already
ASMR is so you know what that stands for
it's the they put it in the meditation
category but that seems unfair yeah it's
like audio I don't know the other three
words but it's disgusting noises
yeah it's a I think it is it
I don't know essentially they you wear
headphones and someone has a recording
of them doing a bunch of like very
whatever I don't think it's a sexual
thing well I think it is fifty-fifty if
you get on YouTube a lot of them get
banned for being overly sexual like
there's a hard implication that this is
definitely sexually charged oh man that
would be super uncomfortable too yeah
they get some very attractive woman in
scantily clad clothing just whispering
no way what about the people who listen
to that stuff do you think people let's
do it like driving on the freeway like
people let's no podcast that's not it
some headphones though it's it's in
their car like it's through all their
speakers you just I'm sure someone does
that dude that's so definitely not good
I would say I'm gonna go out on a limb
and say I don't like that okay wait but
we may need to learn more about it cuz
there there must be sure it's a
something that people have done to
monetize to the sexual side of it but I
there's got to be people who really like
have never felt the touch of another
person or they don't like to I don't
know there's got to be something that
people are benefiting from with it
well it's supposed to give you the
tinglies like you know when you get the
chills like that's what it's for it's
supposed to make you feel like it does
that to me but is the uncomfortable
chills it's like if I was at a urinal
and some dude was like hey man and put
his hand on my shoulder it's that's
that's what it gives me
getting at all yeah I'm not a fan anyway
so maybe next time we'll try the ASMR
thing I only got a couple seconds in no
thank you
so Spencer is a professional ASMR
teacher he runs a youtube account called
a smart fencer mm-hmm it's also a
website dog home um all right cool
Spencer and I are here again Spencer if
you'll notice this is the third episode
that actually this is the fourth episode
but the third that listeners will hear
because one of them was but but uh we
did a but so Spencer and I you know our
conversations always seem to peer into
something that we're both very
interested in a lot of our subject
matter seems to be like we're both on
the same page with it we're able to have
different opinions a lot of times but
were able to have conversation with them
but frankly we have a lot of the same
acquaintances so I think that the the
usefulness there is being able to
communicate those ideas clearly and then
also you know something else talking to
Spencer about is his demeanor and his
his ability to have conversation his
good-heartedness these things open up a
lot more types of conversations with
different types of people so we were
talking about you know having difficult
conversations with people who are
completely difficult with you or
different than you so you know you can't
really have a religious conversation
with someone who has a different
religion than you in a really like
ailment or in a non ill-mannered way I
mean imagine if you're listening to a
podcast and it's two people of different
religions you'd probably be willing to
bet that nowadays it's probably going to
be a terrible thing to listen to because
it's like a debate instead of a
conversation but so it's oh I want so
Spencer will be honey often - I guess
hope hopefully teach conversation and
teach how things are going to go here
and how we can have different types of
people interacting and how different
types of people can have these difficult
conversation these interesting
conversations difference of opinion and
that's something that I think that our
world has kind of let let fade away and
let float away
is like just because you know one bad
thing about person or a person is just
because you have a difference with them
just because there's different beliefs
that you both have you hope we we
accidentally hold on to these things and
then we don't let ourselves progress
forward even have a conversation so it's
like oh there's one thing about you that
I don't believe so we're not even gonna
talk about it anyway just diving into
the depths of conversation exploring
topics you know philosophy psychology
things are we that we're very much into
obviously health nutrition fitness stuff
like that and then really whatever comes
along if you so anyway Spencer will be
on here quite often if you enjoy our
content if there's if you start to get a
grasp for the cut type of things that we
enjoy talking about if you head over to
my YouTube and just like comment like
hey talk about like the origins of the
tooth fairy or talk about like what is
fear and what is fight or flight or you
know whatever you want us to talk about
that's relevant
so anyway Spencer welcome buddy good to
see you
it's getting nice you know something
habitual things doing things over and
over we're starting to do these once a
week at least have the conversations
where the roof court never not and it
has been nice you know I'm a very
secluded person usually usually I've
been slowly trying to like hang out with
more people but just the consistency of
like knowing that like Monday night
we're gonna text you Heather and be like
hey man what's been on your mind this
week what do we kind of want to get into
tomorrow so it's a nice habitual thing I
kind of like to pretend that we're gonna
be all 80 year old men one of these days
meeting at a coffee shop once a week to
talk about the books that we've read
over the weekend you know it's fun man I
appreciate your friendship
I appreciate you as well and I can't
wait to be an old man I don't have
anything to do but things yeah what is
the difference between us in an old man
really like like their their view on
life is so different yeah Oh old people
like we slowly just get more rigid and I
feel like if you don't flex this muscle
like a lot of people don't do this at
all like you I like to romanticize being
old and just doing philosophy and
hanging out
and saying words right but I really hope
that I don't get to the point where I'm
so rigid and how I feel because I've
reinforced it for so long that I just
don't get to do that anymore
oh yeah because yeah if you decide
exactly who you are at a younger age
you're like well this is exactly who I
am forever you don't get explore
anything cool for the rest of your life
right now how boring is that
it seems kind of boring it does I like
the I get my hair cut down the road from
the barber shop I've gotten cut there
twice now in just the conversations with
them couple older gentlemen their view
on life I mean even outside of them
being older gentlemen at all just as
human beings their view on life is very
wonderful I just find myself wanting I
just don't want to talk and you want to
listen to what they have to say and I
think that a lot of our generation and
especially right now we're kind of like
relearning what what they've known and
like like what the older people are like
hey slow down enjoy your life look
around do you like you don't have to
like escape with all this technology you
don't have to do all this intricate new
new entertainment stuff it seems like a
lot of times older people can slow down
and enjoy the world but either way I
mean it's funny because we talk about
old people in that sense now it's just
like one little genre of human beings
but last podcast I think we talked about
old people in a completely different way
like we're referencing the Boomer thing
for hate it's a silly way to get to
converse with people like the wizened
old person hmm like somebody that has
taken all their knowledge and applied it
and it's just like this nice gentle old
person who's just trying to help others
right that's awesome we love those on
you it's the people that haven't
challenged any of their beliefs since 17
and just have lived this complete rigid
I do the same thing every day life right
yeah and they don't you know and that's
the thing is if you have a beliefs that
you feel strongly about I mean you don't
have to sit there and defend your
beliefs against other people but I think
that researching in learning about your
things like like if you reference the
entire rap of rest of your life off of
one documentary and you saw on Netflix
when you're 11 you know like maybe
that's going to send your trajectory
down
and you're gonna like happily learn all
these things of what that sent you down
but like just having the one documentary
and saying this is final truth and
anybody who argues with this truth I'm
gonna yell at or whatever you kind of
just keep following knowledge because a
lot of the times if you're not following
knowledge you're not questioning
anything if you're not questioning
anything you're just not growing at all
yeah and I guess it is the old people or
people that have had a very fixed
mindset their whole life are incredibly
sour old fellows hmm right right but if
people have decided that they're going
to question all their beliefs especially
the ones they hold to be the most true
which are the ones you need a question
and they continue to do that forever
they will probably be very excellent old
people right I don't know I think it's
hard because you know we can't just be
like you know addressing again old
people just seems silly to even say
these words old people but a saying that
that what they think is wrong just
because I haven't explored anything else
we've got to make sure we're never we're
never doing that like but again just
being able to have differences in
beliefs and differences of like in
understanding that we have differences
it's super important and I think that a
lot of that gets lost by the wayside
because there's a lot of there's a lot
of wonderful teachings that a lot of
older people have that are getting lost
by young people just shutting down not
listening so like you know meet you and
I for example we enjoy learning and
depth about religion and philosophy and
these things but not a lot of people do
so like for example let's say a
grandfather is talking to his grandson
and he's talking about he's trying to
teach him overall what he's trying to do
is turn teach Evan Morel he's trying to
teach him about he's trying to teach him
you know how to be a good good man when
he grows up but he's doing it through
this feel of religion so this the Bible
says this and the in whatever whatever
religious that you're talking to them
about it
the young person nowadays is I'm not use
this word correctly but smart enough to
know that there's there's other people
have questioned that you know they maybe
they've seen things on the internet
their friends have different religious
beliefs everything's also mixed now
there's so much that we can know that
the meaning of what the old person is
trying to teach the grandkid is being
completely lost because it's through
this message this boat of religion of of
something that the young kid doesn't
understand and we don't allow ourselves
to listen to each other
well enough in this culture to let to
really say like okay so you said these
exact words I know what you actually
mean so I'm going to talk to you about
that but what we're actually saying or
what's happening is they're saying
something we're like I don't agree with
the words that you're saying we're not
trying to understand like what does he
mean in but but it is difficult a young
person versus some old person a younger
person doesn't understand that this they
may not be talking about everything so
I'm metaphysical that may have been
super confusing I apologize but it's
kinda the lens that they are speaking to
you is inherently shutting you down from
even listening to them because it's at
face value it is something that you
reject or at least I personally reject
to such a hard degree that it's just
like an automatic shutdown it's like
when you are attacking people's beliefs
and they just completely shut down
DoubleDown gonna be the same thing so if
they took that same lesson and just put
a different lens on it and it wasn't
under the guise of something that you
would disagree with as like a truth
you're all gonna get a lot more out of
it and if you can like look at these
people and what they're trying to tell
you and just kind of take like an
overhead view of what they're saying to
you rather than and right right you
extrapolate what they're trying to say
yeah and then maybe apply that or at
least decide that I see your reason but
and I don't believe that and then that
reinforces you where you're at so even
if you disagree it's helpful the people
are saying stuff that they believe that
you definitely don't think is true at
least gives you more data on why you
think what you think is true right
exactly
do you think that we've accidentally
trained ourselves to I keep saying that
to actually train ourselves to argue
instantly against things that we don't
instantly agree with so like when
they're presented with us we don't even
realize
but we're just talking and already
arguing before we stop and think like oh
this is a person's opinion what they
said sounds like this but hmm I know
them this is their background here's
their let's look at this situation what
they probably meant was this when you
when were just in this free active state
which our whole society is and not our
whole society is in it's it's not
allowing us to stop and be like okay
this is what this person means so what
I'm getting at is young or just
different type of people are not being
able to have conversations because we're
not being able to listen to and say this
is what you meant not here's what I
heard from my interpretation we need to
be able to say okay maybe I
misunderstood you is this what you kind
of said the I think just the the
explanation of that we were talking
about conversations and going meta
conversations I think that's a lot of
what the important thing is that you and
I are trying to make sure it's clear to
is is how to have conversations it's
something that I'm like relearning how
to do something that you don't realize
it but someone letting you talk for
three hours is something that hasn't
happened I don't know ever in anyone's
[__] life so I get talking and it's
like oh I have these intricate intricate
you know things to say and I actually
meant this but if someone had to cut me
off two minutes ago or in two minutes of
what I'm saying it's gonna get construed
so I think just unwrapping understanding
each other for sure I think it's hard
because there's a you just we don't use
the same language either like words
don't mean the same things for us and
elder folk mm-hmm and they're what they
hold true in the world is not what we
hold true in the world so it's almost
like we're it's like an alien concept to
be what they are so it's very hard to
empathize with them because it's just so
ludicrous to me that these people hold
these beliefs so you're already starting
out from an extremely disadvantaged
point because you got a weave through
all of this and try to get something out
of it and then a lot of times people
that hold really strong beliefs that
they've had for a long time just don't
have a lot of nuance to them and there's
not a lot of extrapolation to be done
because this is so incredibly true to
them so they'll say a punchy statement
and they're not gonna explain it because
that's a truth of them they never had to
explain it why will they because this is
true right that's what the that's what
the news has top you know it's it's kind
of a way of thinking now though the news
has taught you don't have to know that
much to have this point in end all and
all other arguments like nobody can
argue it if you just say this sentence
and that's the news kind of accidentally
teaches that too we have a lot of people
that are caught in that I think the news
is a very low ego thing that happens you
know cycle really just keeps you away
from like finding who you are in your
true self because it just keeps pulling
you back in all this [__]
right I mean I calling you back
everybody has news though I mean
everybody has a different variation of
news or a version of the news but I
think that like with the Union that we
I'd say we're on the same page the news
we're talking about is let's say the on
TV
it made mainstream news mainstream
newness right you know the main things
that people are involving it's crazy to
see how news has it's changed like
nothing I'm something I've been watching
news forever you know news has never
super been my thing but uh I don't know
I just think I've seen about nine eleven
you think about the news that day right
like nobody was probably really watching
the news there's probably a select
amount of people like I don't know for
sure but is probably come out of people
who were watching The Morning News they
normally do but not nearly even half as
many as like these we didn't know about
threats so much and then 9/11 happens I
remember like I guess I don't remember
exactly how it happened but I was so
young and I can imagine that like waking
up the morning was was very different
like oh nine eleven on the news now I
can't imagine what could catastrophic
event would really feel like that now I
feel like every day we wake up with
breaking news we wake up with oh there's
another school shooting and then there's
also this thing when we're like we need
to not talk about school shootings so
it's another popular thing so we're not
talking about him anymore it's it's
weird I wonder like the the difference
between the 9/11 example is just a
moment in time of so back then to now
what do you think the the repercussions
of the changing news will be for the
future when the news is different and
weird now
I think the problem is like we're so
desensitized to big stuff cuz the
world's so bad and there's been such a
big paradigm shift in how we view news
and how the news gets to us because of
the financial incentive and the
traditional news is just dying because
it's just not know nobody likes it it's
just [__] so they got to be more and
think actually more more outrage more
more divisive nests and the the monetary
aspect behind this has kind of ruin all
these things and it's actually not
allowed us to even feel strongly about
any of these travesties that happen and
I would love it if it died off because
these things are extremely important
when they happen and we need to take
hard note but when you have a new cycle
and two days it's like when this this
story of like a shooting or a tragedy
goes on and in three days it's something
else and we just are so inundated with
not actually feeling the pain of that or
the gravity of the situation that it is
overwhelming it's too much information
yeah that's exactly right it's too much
information we it's not healthy for us
to have too much information like this
it's like as much as as a fellow human
being if I did know that there's
starving kids in Africa that makes my
heart hurt but I shouldn't wake up every
morning and see if they're starving kids
in Africa I can't live my life with my
heart hurting all the time you know like
we can't know all the drama the things
that we have our blood pressure has
risen the things that have like caused
our body our chemical [__] pods here
to just do all these crazy things just
by watching the news every hour of news
that you've watched of things that
actually really weren't relevant to you
they were just kind of passing that time
and giving you some in-between
information in you know you texted
people you post it on your Facebook you
did these things because you saw them on
the news
well they don't they don't actually
affect you a lot of times if you look
back at the things that you cared for
strongly that the news told you to care
about you know the last three years
really what part of your life have they
changed like what what have they given
you like the things that matter to you
in your life have they affected them in
in the the correct way I think that the
24-hour news stream is not good for our
health it keeps us thinking about the
wrong thing so you can't constantly like
if you want to not if you
stop being a drug addict you can't wake
up and just look at some drugs on TV
every single day and and and have drugs
on the table every single day you know
you go if you want if you want to get
away from something that's tragedy
something that's bad you got to insert
things that are good you got to wake up
and you gotta like what do I like today
not what tragedy is going on what do i
oh I want to learn how to play guitar so
I'm gonna put like some light guitar on
I'm gonna play piano put light piano on
I want to learn how to sew so I'm gonna
watch a sewing station we can't just
like keep learning about what's bad bad
bad somebody has to obviously we have to
pay tests what's going on the world you
can't be blind to it but I've got a fun
little experiment for everyone to do so
for the next week or pick a couple days
delete all your social apps delete all
your media apps and then don't watch TV
and then focus on only stuff that you
actually like to do like don't waste any
of your time putting any energy into
[__] that it's just wasting time or just
can't like taking your conscious
awareness away from stuff you really
like to do it sound like I like the
creative right there's a lot of things
that I enjoy doing that I just don't do
because I spend time and taking just
just this [__] media that is not helpful
at all right and just see how you feel
like it was profound when I did it
didn't you just recently like do it
again yeah about two weeks ago three
weeks ago wait so so what exactly is you
just delete you the apps or what do you
I deleted YouTube Instagram Twitter
Facebook stopped watching news and I
stopped playing video games okay how
like to do a bunch of stuff and I just
don't do it like I like to shoot I like
to do archery I play D&D so I do a lot
of creative writing right I like to play
cards with my friends like there's like
a lot of things that I enjoy doing that
I don't do because I'm too busy being
distracted and I feel like this news
cycle like all this this terrible drama
that is the real life news is just so
embellishing and you just get slowly
more and more into it more and more into
it I mean it really is just a bad drama
TV I mean I would say it's equally as
bad for your brain it's just watching
trash TV it seems like the people who
watch it though the way that they
freakin award things on the news is they
they make it seem like if you're
ignoring the stuff
idiot you are so stupid if you're
ignoring this stuff so the people who
are listening to our like of course I'm
the one listening to it I know people
who aren't listening to it they have no
idea what's going on like that's people
who watch the news are walking around
talking to other people who watch the
news saying they have no idea what's
going on but has it made your life
better is it is it actually I don't know
I I don't want to just throw like oh
I'll news or like you should ignore
everything that's going on politician
wise but like man this stuff is [__]
right now it's it's it's really weird
there's a lot of like I mean anybody can
watch any documentary it's about like
what's actually going on here and all
the the marketing that they're they're
doing and all the you know people in
charge who are putting certain ads in
front of our eyes all of our attention
being purchased our data all this [__]
it's the news is it's not it's not
fabricating real life for the for the
Watchers it's just not real life
it's it might be a little bit a little
bit it's really something is really
happening and they might be talking
about a little bit of it but whatever
they spin on it is not real and you got
to look at the financial there's a
financial reason that all these things
happen like they just want to get clicks
they want to make you mad so you come
back Facebook puts ads in front of you
that are gonna make you upset
they put post in front you that are
making upsets so you engage more so you
make more ad revenue like your
consciousness is just being sold and if
your attention is just being sold on the
other side of that I feel like it is
everyone's civic duty to understand what
is happening in the world it's not good
to turn a blind eye to the entire world
and just live your I mean you can't just
live your quiet happy life and never
engage with it but it is important to
understand these things but it's also
important to understand the thing just a
lot of nuance and a lot of other factors
into consideration of them just what
you're being told like you need to be
able to form a whole congruent opinion
on all these political things based on
like your philosophical beliefs and
that's why I think philosophy is really
important because it imposes a bunch of
questions that you need to come to terms
with how you feel and it allows your
worldview to be more linear and sound
and then you can have better political
opinions because you know you really
believe and you've really actually
thought about it a lot of these people
that watch the news
not thought about these things they just
have they turned on TV one day they
believe what their dad did and now
they're upset but why like why is if
your question why am i mad about this
why is this happening is this is what's
happening ethical like why am I upset
this very question to ask
yeah I mean people people I think I
think what's happening I mean just
summarizes the whole news thing it sucks
because I think people are being kind of
catapulted into having arguments that
aren't really theirs they're kind of
just being used as a mouth as a talking
whatever like a puppet for for all these
peoples whatever agendas and this is
like on all like a lot of sides of the
political the whole thing I mean it you
know even saying so voting like okay I
want to vote and who do I vote for like
what what does it mean like like how do
I learn to vote I'm sure there's like
plenty of simple things but there's also
there's probably a great answer to that
there's probably like you can type in
certain things and just gonna give the
answer and now I'm saying it out loud I
think I would love to like learn exactly
like where can we send people to like
you want to learn how to vote or want to
know about the basics of voting here you
go but a there's so much [__]
information and there's so much
information that's biased there's so
much information that has very much
headlined clicky stuff there is people
with more money than other people who
have purchased more of your data than
them there's like for example the
election like I don't want to dive too
far into like the political stuff but
just as a basis of what I'm saying what
I'm saying the whole thing is nutty is
there if you weren't going to vote so
say that you're someone who like had
just has cable and you've never voted in
your life but based off of your search
history you're a [__]
you're an [__] you're a turd being
and just lives by yourself out in the
woods but you have cable well people
with money and power know these things
know everything about you because of
your data your search history your Alexa
your whatever these people can then say
oh this guy's never voted for it but
he's likely to vote for this candidate
and that's our guy right there that's
our candidate so let's make sure that he
particularly gets our ad six miles down
the road
some liberal nice really whatever
whatever people in they're gonna get a
completely different ad based off of
their watch history so that right there
like the the pinpointing the targeting
of people like in their intelligence
people and they're like previous beliefs
just I mean knowing that information it
changes everything to me it I don't know
that I have answers for any of that like
that's just craziness right that's so to
me that says like okay so clearly the
whole thing is broken because that's not
I don't know if it's cheating but it's
something kind of weird it's it's way
too tactical for an election because
election what's the point of it you know
like we want we want it's just a bad
system in the debates that they have are
not actually debates they just they're
okay the debates are hosted by news
organizations that are for-profit that
have agendas and they will throw people
bad questions on purpose and I guess I'm
voted in like this is so obviously just
[__] [__] yeah it's just obvious
this isn't in one side versus the other
side this is the whole thing the entire
thing the structure of it is Dickie this
whole system that we have and we've just
allowed it to be ingrained with
corporatism is just ruined everything
but if I'm gonna give some tips if
you're gonna pick a candidate go look at
who was given the money and then look at
like cuz you can see publicly who their
donors are hmm go see who's given the
money and then go look at their policies
you say Oh oils given this guy a bunch
of money I always got a bunch of oil tax
cuts like okay like these things add up
like if you can see who's paying for
this you can see where this person's
gonna do even in regards if they're not
saying these things you know what
they're gonna do because something's
lining their pockets so I would say go
go seek that out I'm not gonna tell you
who to vote for but it's hard to seek
that out though man because you start
going into these rabbit holes and it's
just all this I don't want any isn't
fake news I'm a goddamn podcast but
thanks me reason all fake news yeah
that's what I'm saying is it's all fake
news it's all [__] but but so here's
the thing is I would never I'm not
trying to advise people to not vote I'm
saying we need to learn way more so like
something Shane that I had a
conversation with about and then I was
just bringing back up I would love to
you I'm I'm not super savvy from the
whole road
process I want to like go through it and
I want to go through it out loud on this
podcast I want to try to offer not too
strong opinions you know because I know
like I crack my fair share amount of
jokes about like the Trump thing but
it's not so much about him in like him
as a person as much as its again this
whole thing is just ridiculous like like
a look at what happened you know but but
anyway I think what it is important to
notice because a lot of people like
let's say the far far left the crazy
people are getting to this conversation
Spencer and they're like this whole
thing is [__] and they're doing this
who love uh and then they're going
outside and they're saying this is bad
yeah we need to change this like people
don't talk about these things or or
notice that like hey we're on a [__]
rock hurling through space and to
survive and to be successful and not
kill each other and not die of
starvation we have to have culture we
have to have society this is something
that needs to happen and unless you
person on the side street just yelling
and complaining about it of what other
people are doing unless you have a
better idea it's kind of like what's
happening right now so I think that that
speaking of things like the structure of
how everything is and the the entirety
of of all this is is super important but
like we're not trying to just [__]
throw it all under the bus and say it
sucks or just complain about it I think
that it's it's nice to speak about in
like I don't know if like Spencer you
and I we always get going down far
rabbit holes of like even you know
far-fetched ideas like man what if like
we didn't have a president and we just
had like seven dudes who you know like
it's fun to to extend like your what if
philosophy from and take your
conversations into into those areas and
extend like I wonder what could we do
like I don't know everything what could
we do and have those conversations with
your friends instead of like the here's
exactly what they're doing what I'm
doing and this is wrong this is right
and blaming people and you got to get
away from status quo bias just because
it is like this now doesn't mean that's
how it should be a lot of people are
like we were capitalist nation like our
government is dis out is this how it's
gonna work and we can't change it at all
okay this is American
okay well that's pretty regressive and
maybe we should think that this is a
pretty [__] system and everyone can see
it maybe we should change it and maybe
you should talk about that yeah and then
but but there is also love I mean we
kind of hit a dead end with that because
then it loops back around to a lot of
people's religions like this this one a
lot of people I don't even want to dive
too far into religion anymore really on
this one but it's hard because you hit a
lot of speed bumps but I think the point
of it is being able to have open
conversation and open dialogue in in
being able to really understand like let
your brain wrap wrap itself around that
like there's seven point six billion
[__] in the world and they know
a lot of different things 100% in their
heart the same way that you 100% in your
heart know them so what the [__] man
things are clearly like it's okay that
people have different beliefs there's so
many different beliefs but when they're
stopping progress and stopping all these
things it's frustrating but we must you
go out in the world and start having
conversations a lot of people are going
to stow them all the [__] out of you you
just gotta have good faith in it and
then just keep going out and doing it
like a lot of these people that don't
have the mindset of hey let's have an
open conversation they just want to
tribe up and attack you mm-hmm it's not
gonna end well like you're not gonna
have a good conversations people but
that is me shouldn't try to because
you're never gonna get anywhere if you
don't try and you're never getting where
if you just attack people because
they're gonna double down it's gonna
make it worse
so if you really want to espouse your
opinion you think it's very good you
should have a very nice and quiet
conversation about it and then not get
upset when people disagree with you yeah
yeah you're totally right but I think
also taking it on your own take it where
you want it like me I'm very interested
in in in everything and I want to
explore all realms of possibilities and
like I want to remain a disbelief and
like learn what you think but I don't
think that I'm like why I'm owed you
your opinion so I shouldn't invite
someone who has a very opposite opinion
of me for them to come like yell at me
on my podcast or or somebody like like
if there's somebody in your life that
their opinion is vastly different from
you but they don't they don't understand
the conversation
skills the they think that things are
all debate they think that things are
like facts and facts negate everything
that you just said it's whatever facts
is for you and where'd you get them like
theirs yeah yeah having civilized
conversation and that's not a champion
belief because you want to be your your
dumb lizard brain just wants to dominate
people and win I want my words to be
your words [__] you my ideas better and
then and not a lot of people aren't like
that because that's just how we are at
our core you have to learn how to not be
like that because we just come out the
box like that
so you most people aren't gonna be very
helpful but we should at least try yeah
we should definitely try just meet new
people and see what they think and let
them to say what they think and learn
about it and you can learn something
from everyone if you talk to everyone
like they know something that you don't
you're gonna get a lot more out of
conversations I mean most attend they do
know something you know if you really
think about what they always do everyone
does something you don't know that's
just I would go on a limb and say that's
probably a fact I mean it's definitely a
fact like they they know if their
mother's name you don't know their
mother's name boom one thing they don't
know that's something they could teach
you oh you could have just learned
someone else's mother's name you miss
violent cuz you're being a [__]
lessons they want to teach you too and
maybe you can at least you can learn how
not to do stuff to people like if this
is somebody that you really think is
really [__] in the bed like maybe you
could just learn oh this is a less like
you did something bad and I learned a
lesson from it now you win so and if you
really don't like this person they
really believe stuff that you don't like
you can at least learn something but
when you're too busy being right you
miss out on lessons yes when you're so
enveloped in this person is an idiot and
this person is this and your opinion of
someone and and I'm right and you're
wrong
you don't have any room in your head or
in your intake right here of taking in
them teaching you anything yeah you're
too busy filling it in with them being
on there's a problem with this though
because a lot of people make a lot of
points and very bad face when you just
are saying stuff to like just like
dominate you in some way and they win
yeah they're making bad faith arguments
like this whatever they're saying is not
coming from a place of kindness or
empathy or reason and they don't
actually believe these things that are
saying these things to be hurtful or
they're saying these things tucked own
you quotes yeah dude do you think that I
mean conversation is some
the language conversation has definitely
been changed and kind of like weirdly
stripping away in strange ways obviously
just because technology the internet
social media texting like our shortening
of texts our shortening of words I think
I've talked to you before I notice when
I'm writing my like if I'm writing a
book like oh I'm this is a chapter for a
book that I want to author one day it's
very different person that is writing
that when I'm typing on my Facebook wall
or it's special I'm tweeting like the
the misinterpretation of of language
that has happened just with that just
within our own selves like sometimes we
changed what we really mean but it's
definitely changed language has kind of
broadened without any explanation of it
and in our we're all trying to navigate
that it's super weird but it's I think
it's important for people to understand
that different words and different
terminologies and stuff aren't always
the same to you and another person we
have to look inside like okay give it a
second what does this dude really mean
what is he actually saying not the exact
words well this word means this so and
you said this word so Mahmood no you're
right and I'm wrong it's we got to
listen to what they're saying not not
the words that they're saying intent is
important but you also before people get
their guard up before this gets heated
you can just define terms they say like
faith is like for grillage people say
the word faith but it means a very
different thing to a lot of people right
that's like hey like what does this mean
to you like would you define this more
me please or like you're a political
debate ask them to define a word because
usually if you've been living in a
different bubble than they have this
word holds way different connotations
and denotations to them so if you can
understand how they mean that word you
can definitely communicate with them
better because we're saying the same
words but they just don't mean the same
things dude i I think that that's
something we should really like dig a
hole like heed this part of the podcast
that is actually a pretty big deal the
misinterpretation that we're having of
the exact same words like we are so in
our heads that we don't realize that we
don't know like like two years ago when
someone is someone was talking to me
about the word spirit or whatever
I would be like that's something for
them that's something that they feel bah
bah but like now that I've felt my own
versions of spirituality and whatever
that [__] means to me like I'm able
to know what they mean when in so I can
have more compassion with them so that's
just something like through my own
experience that I'm making a connection
obviously with that but I think that
entire versions of words faith is
another good one the word ego like our
first podcast we defined ego I think
that being super cocky and super
confident all of us a lot of people our
age especially knowing that we know
words and we hear someone say something
so we take it out of context because
we're like oh they're saying this about
me but we're forgetting or take we're
not taking that person into
consideration we're not taking oh what
did they actually mean what's their
knowing of this word because I mean if
you're a thirty old man and you've read
a ton of books and there's a
seven-year-old girl who's read four
books and you guys are having an
argument about what faith means the word
faith what the definition of it is it's
going to be different you guys are
arguing different points but you're both
think you're wrong well there's chances
that a lot of times you're arguing as
the seven year old and you don't need to
be arguing at all you need to just be
like let's get on the same page of what
we're talking about the same word right
I think it's pretty important yeah words
have to mean stuff and we need to at
least have them mean the same thing to
communicate a big thing in philosophy
almost every philosopher well when
they're doing a lot of writings they'll
be very very very meticulous in
describing what these words mean to them
and exactly how they're using them to
deliver a more eloquent concise point
and we just throw words around we also
really devalue words as well then when I
condensed them yes the the power of
words is really devalued you see when
people like younger kids will awful time
say a lot of bigoted words like just
says jokes because they just I mean
we're just don't mean anything to you
like these are just fun words that
you're saying but once you just get a
little older and you start to realize
like these things are really potent like
these words have been used in very bad
ways mm-hmm
these are these are powerful and then
you sort of think about it and like oh
maybe like everything I say is pretty
potent if you make it that way
in order for society to function boards
have to mean stuff yeah I mean yeah
that's that's a super big thing I mean
in in little kids knowing more words but
like knowing of them but not really
really grasping them that's got to be
like not super great super it's got to
be a little more confusing than anything
I think dude like just [__] difficult
yeah language is so difficult in its I
think that it's kind of being a little
bit swiped out from underneath us like
and if we're not careful if we're not
you know we could we can't just shorten
everything we can't just convince
everything so if you're like hey man
give me one give me a five-word sentence
on what religion is you can't do that
that doesn't say you can give them a
five-word sentence but now you have just
given your view of religion on a
five-word sentence you just put a box
around this thing and religion is just
the word that came to mind but like any
of any of these words that people want
to condense so much ego for example like
that's a word that like every time we
talk about it seems like it's like it
we're defining come from a little bit
different of a stance because it's it's
talking about something I mean think
about consciousness like I read
conscious by Annika Harris and like I
read the book and I'm like man I feel
like I still don't know if I could fully
describe what consciousness is to
someone if they asked me see it's we we
have to remember how complicated
languages and what a lot of times we're
doing here in today's world is [__]
fighting people over misinterpretations
of language and misinterpretations of
the dude wasn't able to explain what he
actually meant because he didn't have 17
hours to tell you his point but we need
to work with what we're given you know
yeah there's a double-edged sword of
that though because a lot of people
don't even know why they believe stuff
so when you get them to explain it it's
just kind of a train wreck because they
haven't actually had to think about it
at all but that's the thing if one if
you're explaining something you're right
so you don't know what [__] you're
talking about be like actually you know
I think I'm stupid yeah maybe just don't
know this thing and it's super okay to
not know stuff or
but I will say that I would really like
it if more people that had strong
believes to held them for a reason
mm-hmm you know because I think that
this excess we definitely need to give
people a lot more leeway and explaining
the stuff that they need to and stuff
like Twitter is really ruined speech
because that 140 character limit is not
conducive to a nuanced mm-hmm complete
explanation of anything it's got to be
short and punchy and Mimi and that's
what's rewarding you know in if it
insults them perfectly to the people who
are listening to it then you get more
likes and you know there's got a slap
but it's not helpful
it's got to be bass boosted yes cool man
let's let's not dive too much farther
and that we will in coming episodes
these are thinking oh man I'm in the
chair that just randomly sinks down all
the time see you later I would love to
talk a little bit more about philosophy
go so the the bio that that I've like
that yours is is armchair philosopher
and then mine is a junkyard philosopher
I just enjoy I mean I I don't know what
I claim to know and I don't really know
what I know yet but I I enjoy a
philosophy of all aspects um I will say
my favorite I gotta say Alan Watts and
Carl Jung probably probably might my top
two Alan Watts it's like a pretty easy
obvious one like anybody who likes
anything in the realm of what we like
usually usually is into some sort of
Alan Watts oh you don't know Alan Watts
is al an waa TTS on YouTube or Spotify
and people have done some really cool
[__] with his lectures you probably
recognize his voice it's just really
nice to listen to I like to go on walks
just put him in add phones Carl Jung is
yeah what was he scottish i don't know
much about him personally i just know
about the the test in a lot of his
teachings yeah yeah yeah yeah he's a
dude yeah he's great and those are my
top two who you talked to you
philosophers yeah that's rough okay so
this is something i narrow down it to is
though i've done
like a lot of research on and I've done
a lot of reading me and one of my
friends he wants to be a philosophy
professor so beautiful and I work out
with him every night so he's probably
spent three hours talking about
philosophical points almost every single
day well it's cool because now I'm going
to make you bring him with you on the
podcast I told him I want him to come
here he's so cool I was great if he'd be
down that really would be cool top that
later
my two favorite I would say also I
apologize for the noise you're hearing
I'll try to edit it out as best I can
but I had a little bit of a basement
flood and it appears that they're fixing
the Plouffe the pipes upstairs right now
so sorry Spencer continued buddy
so rough cuz this in company this
encompasses so many different like parts
of belief mm-hmm
politically I really like the Frankfurt
School thought which is basically just
all the communist guys I really like all
of them as philosophers they're great if
you like it hey get dick by capitalism
and you think your life sucks cuz you're
being you're selling your time
Marxism go look up the Frankfurt School
of thought and just listen to their
ideas okay can you explain what he's
made of the death I'm not sure the
Franklin School thought is a group of
people around when Marx was alive and
they just kind of had a lot of they just
had a lot of ideas that were pretty
communist and they did a lot of poking
at capitalism and like political
structures and whatnot right and that's
kind of what they believed I really like
them there's a there's a podcast that
does excellent expose on all these
people that is very unbiased it's called
philosophize this if you want to I think
that I've heard their stuff I think they
even I'm YouTube short videos to is
excellent it's very very good and it's
very unbiased very educational
philosophize this is cool and then I a
manual can't I like a lot I don't like
his view on metaphysics this is like
pretty deep in the weeds because you
would have to like to know a lot about
what he's saying but everything else
that he believes I really enjoy who
David Hume is great as well
I can't think that is he's the ultimate
skeptic he's like this a jolly Scottish
man who was just like just the biggest
skeptic but he was always happy like a
traditional mark right of a philosopher
it's like there's a sad insel who just
like never sees the light and it's just
internally tormented but he's like the
well-spoken Scottish man who's all jolly
and enjoys everything but he was just
like a really really strong skeptic
incredible
imagine if Steven Pinker was like hit
but what all he writes is just actually
just you look at everything sucks isn't
you know I talk about all this stuff and
everything is jolly and great and we're
am very optimist but realistically it's
just disaster most of the fingers are
really sad they're very very torn I mean
okay because so thinking about these
things the average person versus of so a
philosopher what does a philosopher
think about they think about this like
like what everything is right like a
like okay well let's define that let's
back up philosophy let's define
philosophy okay before I'm just gonna
interject real quick two of my favorite
grandstanding ideas come from a man he's
French named Albert Camus okay okay he
does absurdism which is basically like a
world like there's just nothing like
this is just complete chaos and you must
be you must be happy and the idea that
nothing has meaning and that's beautiful
and freeing everything is absurd yes
everything Oh everything is absurd that
guy was my jumping off point into doing
all this like learning and I really
really really enjoy his working so if
you want to follow that it's kind of a
catapult into sadness so if you're not
careful yes so that's kind of the
problem because nihilism is what is
before that and I was like the world
means nothing like I'm sad and depressed
my life is meaningless and a lot of
nihilist run back to religion because
it's comfort and it's this it's as hard
belief though your life has meaning but
if you just take one step further I know
or or even hold on to that like that
feeling where you don't have your feet
are off the ground if you just hold on
to that for a couple of months a couple
weeks its life gets really fun over
saying hey I really like discovering
philosophies I'm like oh man okay my
brain is on structuring right now I
didn't realize that it's just it's so oh
I love that it's like my favorite it's
so great to just unfold what you know
to learn something new and you must have
someone else to bounce it off to because
I have more questions than answers doubt
than even when I started like I am way
more puzzled like I spend every day
tiling over like ethically how should I
treat people like it these are my world
views like right there's just so much
nuance and there's no answer and it's so
fulfilling to just work over it oh no
and go a whole day holding on to a
belief you like man I think this might
be like the thing and you're walking
around and you're having like profound
insights about it and then two days
later you're like oh I forgot I even
thought that that was the thing you know
you stumble upon these like awakenings
is a strange word but it's kind of what
it is like just a realization it's a
religion just have more you've been
presented with the worldview or an idea
that you don't currently have and you
get a test it with yours and see if it's
good if this is better than if this is a
better worldview than I currently have
I'm going to adopt it and yet we'll
allow you if you're open-minded to
constantly shift and evolve your
worldview and if you do enough studying
you can have a perfectly congruent
worldview and then you know how to treat
people you know how to act you can
understand that they have different
obvious - you can really understand yes
and you're much more open to ideas
because of this do you think that the do
you think the average listener like has
really had a life-altering like
worldview like a I mean like so let's
say a traumatic a person who's gone
through a traumatic time in their life
they've had a life-altering view okay so
you for example like you talked about
how like your life has been pretty like
it's not too bad but like you are able
to see that you know that life is more
than just a safe bubble of whatever
you've created whenever you have grown
up with you've challenged that and
you've explored the rest of the world
like you've you've left the ground you
walk on be shaky because it's like a
what-if thing I think a lot of other
people say hmm a worldview change like
like being able to actively change who
you are so a lot of people here's a good
example sorry I was flirting around it
when you're 40 years old a lot of people
are like oh I thought I knew everything
when I was 25 and they'll give you some
examples samples of whatever they're
like I was a [__] idiot when I was 25
I like to say things like that
I think that while we're 25 we there's a
lot of people who aren't willing to
admit that when they're 40 that's likely
that's gonna happen or when they're
whatever yet this age it's gonna happen
like these do what you think now is
probably going to drastically change
philosophy like you have stuff like that
like every day the more you learn about
these things or the more you're like oh
I think maybe I believe that it's like a
flip switch where we're like stuff just
man I wish I could like think of like a
movie scene that just like moves the
person is still there but the whole
setting shifts you know what I mean that
sounds kind of what it does when your
worldview shifts you can do ones yeah
okay so say you have to describe that to
a [__] robot someone who doesn't
understand my order someone who has
never felt they've never they've lived
in a cave their whole life whatever I
don't know they've never had some
profound shift and changing what they
believe in I would say if anyone's ever
left or gone to religion you know what
it's like mmm definitely I mean it's
just a complete reworking of how you
view the world and the values that you
hold so I in high school was a very
empirically driven just like complete
rational like if their numbers don't
support it I don't support it like all
this will [__] I'm just not gonna
accept it because this is not the real
world
sure and I took everything at face value
and I denied everything that wasn't that
and slowly as I grew up started think
about things and I wasn't very
empathetic person I didn't look at
things from other people's point of view
I always questioned everything but it
was to be right and slowly growing up
and just doing research on how to think
and all these other people that have
been the great thinkers of our times I
guess and seeing how they think and
bouncing off how I am and then slowly
adopting these things has completely
changed Who I am as a core being but it
didn't happen very quickly so I can't
really attest to what it's like it was a
very slow slow growth and I would
encourage people to not completely
shatter their own world yeah you don't
slowly get into this your egos very
you need to protect it to some degree
you can't just completely be blown up
like you got a slowly challenged
everything you believe if you challenge
everything blue it wants it's gonna be
really overwhelming it in that and that
is something seriously though if you if
you are exploring a lot of these things
a lot of like different philosophies a
lot of psychology when you start to
understand things like more in-depth
alright so that's something with
psychology you know philosophy is right
there at hand but psychology as I start
you know reading psychology books and
exploring more more into that world I
start realizing like you know you start
thinking about when you move your right
arm you know like why did I move my
right arm and in this way and you start
connecting things to different things
that's the travel example about the
right arm but you start looking at
things from a different lens because
your lens is now more intelligent you're
upgrading you're upgrading your hardware
here like you're able to look at more
things it I it does get shaky if you're
not careful I'm definitely if you like
dive pretty deep a lot of like the
people healing like childhood traumas
and doing like hypnotism stuff and a lot
of the stuff that that is in this world
is a little shaky but it's super
exciting so but if you if you feel
yourself like man this feels
uncomfortable like don't retreat from it
but give yourself enough self-love to be
like let's let's kind of explore
something that I enjoy let's let's let's
not watch this next documentary about AI
and in what is reality and all this sort
of stuff you know take a step back and
find your sanity before you go exploring
into it I mean there's an eagle whiplash
with all things too whenever you're
trying to change yourself like your
life's like guitar string and like all
things you're trying to your body's
trying to achieve homeostasis or stay at
a baseline and it realizes that you've
survived where you're at so we should
stay here because if we changed all
maybe we won't survive even if it's for
the better your body wants to hold on
there so when you strum this guitar
string it goes up and it goes down you
get that pulldown effect and that if you
challenge too many things at once
it's going to be very overwhelming your
end up a worse off than you were before
so we just slowly like introduce new
ideas like find just like find one
school of thought to tackle like how do
I feel about like being alive or like
the existence in general like do I think
that there's a God like do I think that
the world is just this chaotic mess that
accidentally happened you're asking
these things for no and you have to have
an answer you can wonder no you don't
have an answer yeah yeah that's the
thing I think that's the thing as people
they say I don't know and they end the
conversation that they're like you know
I don't know but yeah I was just on a
hike and I found myself I noticed that I
was just doing a house for minutes I was
literally just looking at the mountains
in the sky and one position wasn't
moving and I was just kept in this state
of wonder like I wonder what man like
what is this of all these things I've
learned like you know I don't know I
wonder what this is it's just it's so
interesting and you start noticing that
it's just beautiful is the thing is
wonder leads to beauty man it really
does is because you don't know in
remaining in not knowing remaining in
disbelief getting yourself there is
great but remaining in disbelief it's
just super important you don't have to
know you can just wonder something that
I cherish a lot is the fact that all the
philosophical ideas that I hold are not
truisms and that they're subject to
change and I will never know for certain
so I get to spend my whole life
wondering I'm getting an answer is so
[__] boring no I just don't want to
know whether yeah what am I gonna do I
just need to ponder this my whole life
and then through this I get to be a more
efficient effective affectionate person
that's excellent and the pursuit of
knowledge or thought even if it's not
what I believe like at least exploring
these ideas to allow yourself to view
the world in a more wholesome manner
that is more like you can back up your
ideas like hey I feel this way because
of this and this and this and this is
how I see things it's very even if I
respect that a lot I respect people that
they have strong opinions and they have
all these ideas but they've got a very
very deep-rooted reason why and at least
some kind of rationale to getting there
it's when people haven't questioned
anything and they believe things very
strongly that is very upsetting right
it's like hey how can you have these
foreign opinions you've never explored
anything
yeah and you know why wouldn't you want
to explore it feels so good it is very
frightening and I understand that I just
have the perfect personality set up to
really seek these things out and a lot
of people just aren't gonna want to do
that but I think it's a very it will be
very helpful for everyone to just maybe
question where they currently believe
whatever you believe the strongest you
should question it ya know why do I
believe this but but not to say like I
think they're trying to tell me that
that this is wrong and it's not the
absolute truth it's like no it's because
life is is very wonderful when you
question things like life is life is a
journey I mean you dude this is at all
times you're on you can be on a loading
screen of the coolest game ever and just
choose what adventure you're gonna go
down like what character you're gonna be
in and if you just stuck on one
character the whole time you know if you
forget that you can press B and go back
to the [__] loading screen sometimes
you know like you're gonna get maybe
you're super good at being a swordsman
but you can try the archery you know
yeah you have this like magical thing
between your ears
that you can flex all the time just like
a muscle and if you don't flex it how
you got to push all the buttons man you
got to think about stuff go seek new
ideas out I mean maybe there's reaffirm
what you believe
great maybe they don't and no matter
what you are in a better spot so if you
never seek out any of this information
you're just gonna I mean it I think
you're just gonna be suffer really even
silently even though you don't know that
you're currently doing it not seeking
out nuance in life and new ideas and all
these wonderful things they go along
with just like sitting and thinking in
pursuing these these ideas you're just
you're just shorting yourself because we
don't live for very long and you're
really just gonna be you're just gonna
decide at 20 that this is what you
believe and you're never gonna test it
again and then you're gonna go sell your
time to work and then that's it you're
just gonna work and die you just know
you're never gonna enjoy the little
little finer things in life the you have
that this is for sure like the stories
of afterlife like I'm I don't know I
mean you're here now why you worry about
that you got a medal a ground you got a
whole world full of people that have
already thought about stuff you can go
play around with these toys you can do
it in life is you can it's a
choose-your-own-adventure I mean really
think about it it's in life we think
that it's always just looking for
the most happiness but it's actually
just choosing what struggles you want
like what's true what pain do you want
to endure what what suffering are you
willing to take on in this 100 years of
life or however long you're gonna live
it's like we think it's like find
something that's safe and just to hunker
down and that was a way of living them
for a long time but but like we're safe
we have food we can we can explore like
it's it's not you don't have to just
focus on on surviving now we can we can
wonder about it and yeah explore like if
the ideas that you hold so strongly and
I've never questioned so okay if you're
a caveman you get all your caveman
friends do the pointy stick you find the
cave with the one entrance all the ideas
that you hold really strongly have never
questioned or sitting at the back of
that yours protect stab and everything
else that comes in mm-hmm but maybe you
should wander out of that cave and then
go look what out look what's out there
you make oh [__] there's way more world
I didn't realize I was in a cave this is
what I was talking about with the maze a
lot of times people have their back
against the wall and their maze and and
sometimes I feel like the conversations
that I'm trying to have are above the
maze now I'm above the maze saying hey
dummies like remember like you you put
four quarters in and you get you're in
the maze game like and then they're
gonna back oh yeah yeah okay we're
forgot that we were in the maze we've
been here four years and they're just
gonna drop their sword and climb out of
the maze and just come hang out with me
I think when you say the maze I think it
says an s awesome analogy for yes like
life and thinking and whatnot because
it's so easy to just believe your stuff
and barrel down it but hey maybe we
should look at this stuff yeah man take
a look like okay yes you're focused on
your fight focus on your hat as you're
swinging your sword and in your you're
in the heat of the moment you know
experience that and feel that then also
remember like okay wait oh yeah I'm on
earth and I'm and that's in the galaxy
and that's in the universe and I'm just
a human being which has to do with with
evolution and all these thing I don't
probably add evolution to that story but
I just slip down again in this old chair
if anyone ever finds any
philosophical ideas new chair that they
just want somebody even talk about
definitely common in one of these hello
yeah I'd love to go off on one I just
don't really want to get into the weeds
with stuff that people aren't interested
in because what I'm interested is
probably not what other people are
interested in well and that that's okay
though I mean you you're you're my good
friend and this is this is my podcast so
we had talked about we're interested in
but also you know in a supportive way to
teach other people who if they're as
resident into they can kind of know a
little bit and and we could compare
ideas with it to it's all about
discussion you know about just kisses
find someone to talk to talk about stuff
yeah I mean that's the thing too as I'm
like as much as I used to be like so
afraid of comments right like you have a
tiptoe so in over the last few years on
Facebook and YouTube and all these
Twitter especially comments just get
where people find something that they
disagree with and they try to rip you
apart and then it becomes this argument
comments are weird like we because we
never decided like hey guys here's what
we do with comments like we never fully
decided that right and same with likes
it's like do you like this product or or
do you dislike this product when you
give it a thumbs down or do you just
like the video about the product you
know so I think that that I have been a
little bit afraid of comments but it's
something I definitely want to be out
about on this podcast is like amen you
can kind of get it just for what we're
talking about here I'm not claiming to
me anything I'm just gonna be honest
about what we're conversating about but
if you think that there's something that
would spark a good combo that you would
like to listen to or you're like man I
think that these guys might know a
little bit about let's say Buddhism
let's say whatever but meditation maybe
they can teach me or hey I can't seem to
meditate I'm not trying to like say that
I'm some sort of dr. Phil here but if
you can comment well we're gonna read
them and we're gonna you can message me
and tell me why I'm wrong about stuff -
I love to talk to you but yes yeah I
don't what I'm what I'm emphasizing
there is I don't want to do the debate
thing I'm not trying to say these are my
beliefs and we're arguing like it's not
how we [__] have conversation that's
how the internet has started working and
I'm I'm just gonna openly say like I'm
not participating in that [__] I'm not
trying to participate in everything
being a debate and I'm right and you're
wrong I just think that we need to
relearn how to have conversation and
remember that this is the Internet and
there's human beings on the other side
of that conversation so imagine you had
to wait
up every morning and in wave hi to your
neighbor but you just talk [__] to them
on on their their avatar to their
[__] YouTube comments
it's just ridiculous we're forgetting
that we're in the maze and in comments
have gotten weird but anyway I'm hoping
to have good comments
social media is the ultimate maze I was
looking at my Instagram like this is
just not an accurate representation of
Who I am at all like if anyone
approached me and then just wanted to
talk about one of these things actually
just wouldn't enjoy it not even a little
bit like this is just not who I am and
it's not who I want to talk about right
but it's in my past what I posted - just
get the fun clicks like this is my
highlight reel look at me doing all this
stuff but this is just not who I am at
all but to a thousand people to follow
me this is exactly who I am especially
they don't know me is so strange so I'm
really at a crossroads like do I just
take everything down and just start
posting some weird abstract stuff like
what do I do with this weird machine I
have no idea how to use it well here's
the thing man is you are with that
sentence you're kind of it almost seems
like you're like fighting against
something that's that's like you don't
have to fight against it's like you
don't have your Instagram doesn't have
to represent exactly who you are in its
entirety like thinking it ever did that
was our problem it like I was looking at
my Instagram for example when it first
came around it was it just had the
coolest filters and filters at the very
beginning words I can they just weren't
around and I remember I had it took my
first few photos I think were like me
taking for Facebook I wanted to post it
on Facebook but I wanted a cool filter
so I used Instagram posted there and
then copied in posted Facebook so that's
what the start of Instagram was and I
want to say that I I looked at a day and
half like 669 posts like I've never
deleted in posts and I was thinking
about a cycle I wonder if I should do
because I've noticed over the last
couple years what people are doing
artists especially is they're deleting
everything except for like four main
posts and it's cool its artistic and I
get it because it's kind of like your
artistic board a lot of the times for
Instagram but it's also kind of like and
are we doing that because we're under
the impression that that people are
going to your page to get the whole
youth at once because that's not ever
gonna happen that's you know like you
can look through all 669 posts and
you're not going to understand who I am
at all
all your gonna know some things that I
wouldn't been through and some things
that I wore math through some things
that I really went through maybe some of
my friends but there's so much more in
depth about me or about anybody than
just their social media right yeah well
what the [__] is this thing for anyways
like why don't we even use this you
don't figured that out we're just doing
it because it's cool we haven't been
like oh yeah we're just really we're
drinking a lot of beer we haven't
realized that like why are we doing a
beer
like why why am I using this and every
time I mean you're not even you that you
were five seconds ago so every like all
these pictures are someone that is not
always quite literally not me anymore
yeah so it can never be an accurate
representation of who you are and I
don't really know what to do with it so
what is it really like like what not
what do we want it to be what is it like
as it stands right now what is it for
Instagram for a while okay I probably
have a hundred poster over the first 75
is just like a hey look at me look at me
doing the thing I want to be the guy
with a nice cardigan you know you
weren't aware that you were doing these
things though it's not like and it's not
like you were like oh I totally sucked
and I was just like posting pictures of
my bicep and like I really just wanted
attention it's like it's just the nature
of ego and the nature of human being and
then I started I started telling myself
I'm not posting here for anyone but
myself it's just - just a catalogue
things that's kind of [__] - because
if I just want to catalog stuff I would
leave them in my photos so this whole
thing is just a hey look at me I want
cliques in general and I don't think
there's really a way you can escape that
unless you're on there to help people so
I don't really know what the - like what
I would use it for at this point well I
don't know it's hard because I've
noticed if I told you about like what
I've been doing like I'm back on social
media and I'm kind of like it's like a
little experiment for me and I tell you
about the awesome trial run
yeah I've like this may not make much
sense to some people but like taking a
year off from social media I I mean I'm
I would say I pretty thoroughly broke
like my addictive qualities towards it
and I was like super into my phone I
just loved Instagram and [__] but like
now that I'm back on it for the race the
podcast like I'm gonna be on it through
December whatever I've been kind of like
letting myself pick up my phone whenever
and pull it out whenever I just find
myself just like I'm refresh I post
something and if I'm McClure and pull my
phone and I refer see if I got any likes
and all these things and it makes me
stop I'm like what the [__] like Wyatt
you know I claim to be doing this
podcast because it means so much to me
why am i refreshing this post and then
like oh yeah because like we you know as
human beings we have addictive dopamine
tendencies and we have certain ways of
getting things and in the cellphone is a
shortcut to get a lot of those things
really fast and our brains are like I
train remembering that way real hardcore
for many years so it's just funny to
like kind of let myself rip so to say
and watch that I'm just like this
dopamine social media hungry just like
ran ran ran trying to consume more
already I think that everybody needs to
be more aware of what your phone is
doing to you and then just say like why
am i doing any of this why like what is
it yeah and when people delete post
because they don't get enough likes
that's something that's like they you
know really think about that like it
that's something that that's rough
that's that's you shouldn't feel that
way about yourself like if you feel that
way about yourself I want you to like
not feel bad about that but think about
it just just think like man that's
something that you know say a young kid
or like a young like naive kind of mind
would do it like well there's a part of
that that still runs a lot of our life a
lot of us so you're a 30 old man and you
posted a post and only got 5 likes in an
hour and you hate that so you deleted it
well that's not something that like the
real you a real 30 old man would really
like actually care about right like
really think about that that's that's a
younger part of you that's something
that you think that you're not getting
in another area of your life in your
mind your intelligence sees the shortcut
this way to get it and it's doing that
so just take it step and see that it's
doing this it's funny because you
probably don't give a [__] about what
the people that do like it think about
you at a face value like if you were to
meet one of the people you barely know
like you actually don't care about their
opinion at all about how they think
about you cuz they don't know a lot of
time yeah that's funny because people
have internet friends if they don't talk
to in real life we were kind of like
that for a while I'd see if the gym and
I'm like we talk all the time on
Instagram and it'd be like ha ha ha like
we definitely know each other for sure
but we can't communicate at all well so
that's something that like and but we
can have a lot of conversation cuz
that's something again that's
the thing with social media it's never
been addressed are these your real
friends are these your like whatever and
a lot of times it's not but a lot of
times it's just like so you and I this
is something that we'd not have a word
for this but I like we get along very
well
I very much enjoy your company I very
much enjoy talking to you on Instagram
but for me going to the gym was a very
huge difficult mental task for me it was
hard sometimes I would get
self-conscious talking to people
sometimes out it would unlock it would
pull me out of my like mental focus so
as much as I know people and do want to
talk to him that doesn't mean that I
could always be who I need to be at the
gym in like that's the thing is a lot of
times people that's a new thing I don't
know like what what to even put words on
that like so that's something where I
can't show up and be the Jake wrens that
you see on social media the Jake Ryan's
that like you've known most of the time
I couldn't be him when I was at the gym
right but you know now and you knew
about probably even then honestly but
that like it doesn't mean that I don't
actually care about you and it means
that I actually only want you on social
media for likes or something it's just
something that's weird that that none of
us we're kind of assuming that these
things mean this when you do this on
social media but we're not taking a look
at like what what your craziness that's
that doesn't make any sense
you know I we had a very odd
relationship before we became really
close you know yeah weird man I don't
know okay what do we got so we just have
a like a lot of very like all our close
friends like your close friends or my
close friends but we never actually
really connected like until probably
like a year ago yeah and I was like we'd
be at your house it was always like we
are both we're both attracted to being
just the guy and there can't be two guys
that I always felt like a not like a
weird friction but it's always odd it
was just like an always odd interaction
that's crazy I it's crazy to me because
I didn't feel that even 1% really I was
so unaware of that I had no idea I was
literally just probably thinking about
myself that 100
that time like I was probably like
trying to do my performance I was trying
to be such an outward chameleon that and
that's the thing too is like a lot of
people like when I talk about me an
introverted person a lot of people are
like what do you time like you're like
one most extroverted people ever and I'm
like yeah you know but but I mean in you
you know that now but um and it's so
interesting we just assume that the
other person is like maybe feeling the
same thing and there's some sort of like
not tension but it was very interesting
because I I felt like you couldn't be
you with me and I couldn't be me with
you and it was like this weird it's like
you're like the ultimate showman like
like just like the guy you're just being
the guy right now and it was just it was
very odd it was very odd because we have
gotten we just I am so used to just
really connecting with people especially
if I already have friends with them it
was always like this weird distance
between you and I you know it's like the
masks get in the way like it's like I'm
so busy doing I'm so busy being the
chameleon for the 16 people around me I
can't be Jake Ryan's and actually have a
good combo with Spencer a lot of times
do you think some movie like that I
don't know it was just always odd this
is weird yeah it was very interesting
well it's crazy that like two people can
remain in the same you know in the same
I guess position situation but be having
vastly different like I've never even
thought like okay here's another alpha
male and and my alpha is bumping up
against his like it was never any sort
of I don't know we're so wrapped up in
our own heads a lot of the times that
it's that it's interesting huh
um Spencer you know what I do want to
talk about dungeons direct uh I would
like to I mean we could do it you know
we can have a whole longer episode one
of these days about this but can you
give me so one thing that I feel pretty
strongly about is it's kind of popular
for girls to jokingly make fun of this
as a broad statement this damn chair I
swear up and thrown out the door girls
to make a broad statement about like
let's say like oh if you play Dungeons
and Dragons you're nerdy or
oh if you play video games like oh
you're a grown man like whatever
whatever I my my opinions are whatever
it is that you like whether that's like
playing the flute with your toes or if
it's dying all your white shirts blue
every Friday like whatever you love to
do especially if it's by yourself I
really am a fan for people doing things
that's like out that rips them out of
like their friend group into a different
friend group you know yeah I think that
it's important to like see things as not
just like oh that's what a nerd does
because we accidentally make fun of them
so I think we can humanize our interests
when we learned about them that's what
I'm trying to not ramble on about we can
humanize our interests when we learned
about them so that's Spencer we tease we
please teach me a little bit about
dungeons dragons do you want me to tell
you why it's awesome we're going tell
wanted to start with why it's awesome
okay so I think it's incredibly awesome
because you get to sit around with all
your butt's okay let's say you were at a
book but you don't know how any of it
resolves okay so a little preface there
the way it works is you have a group of
people that are the players and then one
dude that plays everyone like every
character in the world makes the world
writes the story or sets up all the
things and then you guys kind of
collaboratively improv go through all
this together and kind of have like an
oral collaborative storytelling moment
it just allows people to okay you make a
character in a world where you can deal
with highly sensitive issues or like
really tense things in a very safe
bubble through the lens of someone else
so you write this really deep character
and you get a deal with a really really
hard problem so that are really
real but you can never touch them in
real life because they're they're just
dangerous you're ever in any of these
situations it's like a life or death
could you give a short example of maybe
one of these situated and you're like
dealing with the fate of Nations or
you're like trying to help these
townspeople like this is a very dire
this is a dire moment that requires a
lot of empathy for these people and
you're like considering other sides but
if you're really in this it's really a
big problem in real life something's
went really bad and you have to look at
this through someone else's eyes that
you have created with all their flaws so
now you get a look at a world through
someone else's eyes that's really torn
up and that teaches you a great amount
of empathy and then you get to tell the
story with your friends and it's this
big bonding experience it's actually I
would trade it for any form of media
forever for the rest of my life amazing
yes it's a very excellent for introverts
too because if you're really locked up
with who you are you get it like go to
this fantasy world you get to be a
different person and then you get a like
hang out with your friends and interact
right be very boisterous you just get a
play someone other than you for a while
well I mean that's the thing is a lot of
times we have to make these masks that
we have to be in public but we get to
make a mess that we enjoy now right so
it is super important yeah I encouraged
I think I always think like young kids
there's a lot to be taught like it's
probably it seems like a very intricate
game but I think if they started like
diving into that world um so it dungeon
the dragon it's it's a board game I mean
that's a terrible it's a tabletop game
tabletop all right yeah kind of the same
thing but it's it's a theater of the
mind so mm-hmm I describe the setting
I'm the game master that's the dude that
deploys every week narrator kind of
essentially so they walk into a bar I'm
like okay well there's a there's a dwarf
bartender she's female she's got orange
hair like very very cunning looks
there's a man in a black trenchcoat in
the back brandishing a Novus dagger he
is very nervous like scouring the room
looks like he's up to no good
there was a bar fight in the left corner
and I just paint this picture and then I
say okay what would you like to do and
then the characters does that what they
want to do and you just have this back
and forth but when you it does take a
lot of trust in each other
and writing ability I mean at first
you're just not get a writing character
so it's not as enthralling but once you
learn the intricacies of all these
things it's like riding a deep character
with the love many flaws and you get a
play through this world it's really fun
and I would say it's the most engaging
thing that I do and I would give it up
for nothing and it's something that I
will always do forever and I really
highly recommend everyone try it at
least once
especially if you like video games like
it is such a violently personal
experience that you'd have dear friends
and no one else is ever gonna have that
- and all these rules that are set up in
this book you just don't have to buy by
them like if this is cooler for me to
just not allowed like just allow this to
happen like this is make pretend land
and we're just hanging out and telling
the story like oral storytelling is such
an important part of tradition and
almost all cultures except for it's gone
because we have the internet and we're
gonna sit down and now if you're not if
you're at a podium or around a campfire
you're probably jackass yes maybe a
little bit storytelling it's important
but it's just a beautiful experience and
I will do with my kids because it's just
opened me up to so many really amazing
people and amazing things and it's just
allowed me to have such a strong bond
with like my close friends that I do it
with like in these you just get so you
become the person that you're playing
and you just get so embel obtain the
story it's just it's it's awesome
it's so satisfying to do did it sound so
fun I feel like it's it's you cuz again
it's people judging it off not really
knowing I mean me personally before
before like I mean cuz Tyler's been into
it for quite a while too before he had
ever like mentioned it to me I didn't
really have any opinions about it but in
the back of my mind I did think I knew
that it was like oh it's just like some
board game that that like your typical
nerdy guy would play yeah its foreign
interference I don't have girlfriends
sit on their mom's basement drinking
Mountain Dew and just go roll dice and
kill dragons so funny that we have these
we don't even mean to but we have these
these postured stored with these
postures towards things before we even
ever interact with them it's so silly
but I think that man that sounds like
this thing about that without the name
not knowing anything but even if you
don't really like dragons the situation
you just said like that is the coolest
idea for a game ever okay so you make up
your own situation you walk into a bar
and here's these things that are
happening now what like the
possibilities that are endless the
excitement that I feel even as you're
just telling me I just want to be a part
of that so can we just make the rest of
the podcast edge
dragons what's our situation oh damn I'm
gonna need a lot more just give me a
world to work in so do you have like
realistic characters like so so when
your friends play with you do you have a
name they just play a static character
for the entire thing they play one
person we've probably played for a
hundred and twenty hours and they've
like I have just depending on their
backstories what their flaws are and
like so you know their characters more
over time - yeah so today you slowly get
to know the stories that curates the
story of antenna you just develop nuance
and everyone flows together and if you
write your back stories - like line up
and then everyone's got and you got
interpersonal problems but then you also
have like world problems and it's this
insane simulation of a fantasy world
that it actually deals with a lot of
real-life philosophical points and you
get to work through maybe your own drama
one of my favorite things to do is play
characters as close to my chest as I
physically can and I go yeah I get to
deal with all my own problems and wrongs
in this fantasy world where nothing
Bad's gonna happen it's just it's such
an amazing like and it's so good for
your brain to like the so I basically
seventy percent of the time I'm
improving so there they can just do
whatever they want so if I put them in a
town they're like hey we're gonna go
down we're gonna go up to the next town
and we're gonna do this thing I'm like
okay I didn't prep for that so now I
have to improv for four hours about okay
well what's in that room then you got to
figure out what's in that room so the
amount of like mental flexing I have to
do right - so improv is is a pretty
important tool I grew up a acting and
grew up I loved the stage so improv is
not a foreign thing to me I think
understanding improv I was thinking of
if you watched the office yeah you know
ever see Michael Scott when his improv
he'd just like ruin he just train wrecks
every situation he's again I have a gun
and now it's just different I think
that's another thing like problem
solving that you learned from games like
that because so your people can't just
be like and I threw a smoke grenade into
the bar and everybody had to leave
because that just derails little thing
right you can but what's the social
repercussions okay now you killed a
bunch of people in the town now the
guards are after you and now you got to
deal with this Heywood your character do
that you're you're like oh this is value
you're a good nature character would you
really kill these people like if you
actually write a character and you abide
by it it will we'll just tell you how to
act can we just say that
real life is exactly like this yeah it's
a simulation of real life yeah big-ass
simulation of real life and you actually
learn a lot this is your adventure here
you guys you can choose your adventure I
this is I'm in the cool I'm in a studio
in my home and I'm talking to like one
of my very good friends on microphones
that I know about and I purchased them
in like when I was a little kid I was
just like I like music and like you can
choose your adventure your adventure
could be like music makes me happier or
paintbrush makes me happy or car hearts
make me happy or being in the woods
doing whatever it is man just use the
Smurf shirts make me so [__] happy
size large Smurf shirts I just want to
spend the rest of my life with them and
you just point at that and they're gonna
open a bunch of other doors I was like
music that opens all these other doors
so um something to do improv is a huge
thing obviously with with with D&D its
most of it I would say it's an 80% of
what happens if you actually were like a
like a thespian we really should do this
together cuz you would really enjoy it
what's the thespian is find that theater
person okay okay can you also define
improv like make sure that's well it's
the it's yes and so it's like you okay
you're in a dark room and there's a
light switch okay well I go flip it and
then you slowly just work off this thing
that's you you're just bouncing off each
other mm-hmm
so can you give an example of someone
who would potentially like let's say
quote-unquote ruin that bar situation
you're just talking about like like how
could they come in as like a train wreck
who doesn't understand like the rules of
what's going on and they just kind of
hold you guys okay is that possum like a
player yeah yeah
like it likes it's a what I'm hinting at
is kind of like a social unawareness
right like you're you're trying to be
yourself so much you're trying to be the
funny guy that you just kind of ruin
this game there was there's this thing
called being a murder hobo that's just
what it's called is epic and so like
usually if you're telling a big
narrative you want to have a pretty
congruent worldview and your characters
want to be deep and they just like don't
fly off the rails and like it so like
okay if you're playing Grand Theft Auto
I just go kill everyone
that's what being a murder hobo is like
you're just like it just causing mayhem
for no apparent reason and it doesn't go
like your character is no point you're
just killing stuff and poking the world
huh that what else can play with you and
that gave you that
real stuff because you just aren't
abiding to a story we're not telling a
story we're just rolling dice and
killing stuff and that's not the fun
part if you want to do that just play
games like video games mm-hmm that will
derail it because it's just you're just
not abiding by our social contract that
we're about to tell the story you're
just gonna go kill stuff and grab the
loot yeah you have to have rules for
games to exist I mean if you like
football even you you if there was no
rules in football like okay you just
score a touchdown but you just keep
running and you go home with a football
cause it's mine now
and nobody else gets to play anymore
yeah you have to have rules I will say
though if you can get everyone together
to tell this story and they all agree on
some stuff you can just like really fly
off the rails if you follow in that like
there's a very very large section of
what is okay culturally in this setting
yeah and I will say that if you don't
have a creative outlet and start to do
creative writing like read a sci-fi book
read fantasy book read a true-crime see
what you like like study themes go enjoy
stuff I was always told myself I was
this rational being and I just not an
artsy guy at all I may learn to play
guitar pretty easily but not to any real
proficiency when I started doing this
and like really really writing like a
lot it just for like five people that we
sit down on the table at and then
watching them really enjoy it and this
has been one of the most rewarding
beautiful things I've ever done and it's
made me flex my creative brain to such a
high degree and I really think those
people that tell themselves that they
aren't creative are just lying to
themselves and it really can be and it's
such an excellent way to express
yourself and it feels so incredibly good
I agree dude I always say it's like a
feedback loop for Shay if she says
anything like I'm not creative I'm like
hey babe will you like sketch this out
for me where you draw this or like what
do you think something like I don't know
I can't because I said I'm creative I'll
show her song and she bug I don't
understand and I'm like you she says
that she's not creative but I'm always
just like you're wrong yes and you gotta
believe me I just gotta allow yourself
to let go just letting go of the words
that you say that you are like oh I'm
not creative that [__] and go do it
yeah it's a human human ability is is to
be creative it's a thing that you get to
do you get to synthesize things your
ideas you get to put them all together
in a very specific way that no one
cut of and that is definitely art and I
don't care if only one person likes it
the beauty about D&D is I get a value my
own ideas and only four people have to
think it's cool it's the only four
people that's just four these four
people yeah that's [__] awesome and
it feels so it just feels great it's one
of the most rewarding experience I've
ever had and I really think that people
should try it there's a bunch of other
games that are like more real-life
setting to like it's not like this yeah
under that same genre of games that yes
so that so that's the world of course
ducks and Dragons but that's so so
tabletop game do you think a lot of them
kind of have that have a little bit sort
of the same yeah you got like sci-fi
games you got like vampire games you
start games it's all about romance like
I really and I don't want females to
think that this is just a dude thing
like this is an awesome thing you should
get your girl friends together and do
and just like hang out and you can just
test all these things it's like a very
excellent thing to do
so one thing with we're texting earlier
this morning about it The Improv
reminded me of it I think I was telling
you this morning about running a bit of
a like a Saturday Night Live things I
tell you about that I'm in high school I
ran it I didn't run it I was in a
Saturday dive thing essentially we were
shut down halfway through because
someone in the crowd was offended that's
something that we specifically had done
oh that's what you're trying to tell me
yeah yeah so yeah I didn't want to say
it all in text but um so what happened
when I was in high school we had just
like the coolest had been in drama
classes and acting and and all that in
our drama class you turn of this like
lenient super cool awesome thing like we
were pretty self-sufficient with our own
stuff so we basically made for like a
senior night a Saturday Night Live thing
to where it's in between like some other
performances of art of like the choir
and stuff like that we would go out and
we would take the stage for 10 minutes
in between and kind of mix it up but um
so we have like individual funny skits
and we ended up doing one and this was
way back away and like this may seem
like absurd now but way back when when I
was in high school this is 2010
and we did a skit where something about
the swine flu this is how far along it
was this is this everybody was freaking
out about swine flu our joke was like
maybe everyone's taking the swine flu a
little too seriously and we have like a
fake like death on stage like a fake gun
like fake again like please put yourself
back in 2010 like this wasn't what
you're doing but what happened was
someone in the audience had recently had
someone in their life that committed
suicide
and so she I don't up chin like stand up
and point her finger you know but she
like it happened to know someone who was
in charge she came and said like this is
not okay blah blah blah and that person
who came up to obviously like we don't
know what to do with these situations
apparently so we got shut down like
literally they're like I'm sorry you
guys can't go and were like what your
time right we haven't even done half of
our skits we've been working on this for
for four months what are you really
saying and we literally had to like
leave like we were done like we weren't
allowed to finish it because our skit on
stage not of all like the you know
whoever at the admit whatever amount of
people were in the crowd that person was
offended
so I forget exactly what the pinpoint
that with the cornerstone of our
conversation this morning but it wasn't
in regards to that the crowd so the
question is is this person's one feeling
valid enough to ruin every else's
viewing experience like are you as a
person allowed to just say I think this
is wrong and I want to shut down or
should you just say hey I'm personally
not comfortable this I'm going to leave
yes like is that because this is a
that's a valid opinion to have like that
is product I do my best to never say
like oh I'm gonna kill myself or like
this makes me want to kill myself
especially when I'm around mixed company
because I don't know like what that's
gonna trigger yeah but you're gonna end
up tiptoeing around a lot of people if
you're if you're following that same
suit you know like yeah but like where's
the line like how much am I supposed to
dance around other people's
internal problems in speech because you
can't just like walk around in the world
like it's just there's eggshells
everywhere yeah but you also need to be
considerate about others like I do think
that that lady was probably in the wrong
I mean good intentions understand it let
me she was assuredly she's in pain
someone next to her just took their own
life and she it hurts her enough to like
I'd be like I need to escape this pain
that I
that's starting to come up so bad that I
need to go tattle or not at all but but
tell someone I mean it's a pretty
intense feeling that she's feeling right
yeah but should she have just left and
yes hey I I don't think this is good so
I'm gonna leave I'm not going to grace
this area with my presence or yeah I
think this this standing up for what you
believe in is being thrown into like
situations like that which is just like
hey you know tragedies happen like this
is of course again this is talking about
this right now is just like there's a
lot of weird ironies because like I was
going to kill myself
and like all these weird that now with
society you know things are way more
offensive but it's kind of what I just
want to address like even that whole
thing I just think we can't continue
this was in 2010 and these are the kind
of things that happened hardcore now it
seems like anyway seems like the person
who is in the crowd gets this like stand
up for what you believe in confused with
I'm an audience you know when you're an
audience member you you be an audience
member you don't shout at the person on
the stage you don't have an interjection
with the person on the stage you you
leave it you don't try to shut it down
you it's I mean just where's the line as
always the question yeah like how much
are we supposed to pander to people when
they're quote offended I really do
taking consideration everyone's feelings
when they're offended about something
because I'm sure it's very valid but the
problem is a lot of people are offended
of bad faith just because they don't
like the person that is offending them
so they're gonna go they're gonna say
whatever they need to say to get this
person away from them or not speaking
anymore like do we complete the altar
Society because some people are offended
I mean this is a very very sensitive
topic and it's also very lot of nuanced
in every single in so many different
corner yeah every every situation
deserves its own consideration but when
do we just make being offended a
personal problem and when is it a
societal problem sometimes being
offended as kind of a your problem if
your sensibility is very sensitive and
you or it's your personal duty to stay
away from things that offend you
but something should offend you no
matter who you are and definitely need
to be changed like slavery and [__] like
that
like race there's certain things where
you totally should stand up for but I
just think that we our efforts would be
better focused if we reserved all our
outrage for things that are extremely
important and not in minutiae because we
get lost and being really upset about a
lot of really small things that I
definitely do matter but on a overall
level if we if people that are more
sensitive or chronically offended would
just focus their efforts to some really
big things they'd probably get a lot
further mm-hmm because but the regular
average person that knows nothing about
these small details of society in life
and they just are not empathetic to this
person will just think they're being a
whiny little baby and then not take
anything they see her seriously right
yeah we have to have empathy but but we
have to have again you know
self-awareness of our own self in that
situation like this situation is it's a
lot bigger than me these this situation
my past my recent history of my personal
life doesn't really have anything to do
with this situation I'm an attendee in
my job in this crowd as as an attendee
so whatever like stretch whatever that
stretches out you know I'm like this is
a theater analogy here but whatever the
expansion of that maybe life's so weird
Jake and so we're dude I don't get it I
just what's it what's the I don't know
you know what we're just trying to
figure out the point of it all all right
like we don't without knowing an answer
again like we're just accepting that I
may not know an answer but I think I'd
have found life and just knowing that
it's weird in exploring the weirdness of
it yeah and there is no answer and
that's kind of the fun part it seems
extremely daunting but that's the beauty
in it mm-hmm my personal belief is that
we just this is just completely
meaningless everything's an accident the
world is complete chaos
that's super frightening but you got to
look at it like that's really freeing as
well because there's no anchors on you
there's no purpose of this you're just
gonna live your truest self and then be
what you want to be
so there's an old Greek proverb not
proverb with the story so believed
Sisyphus is one of the Greek gods or
demigods and he came here with the trick
Zeus he tricked one of the other gods
and he was forced to roll a boulder up a
hill while a vulture endemic for ever
forever and to look at that he was like
oh this is it this is perpetual
suffering but this is an allegory for
life I think you're always pushing this
Boulder up this hill like this is a
constant struggle but you must see the
chaos in this and you must be a smiling
Sisyphus like you must relish in this
like this is what you have so you must
enjoy it this is your only option
yeah I think that I mean complaining is
a strange think a lot of times people
like you can't just stand there like
here's what's happened to me here's what
life is okay like you're still living it
though so I'm gonna go over here because
you're kind of grumpy yeah being a being
a victim only hurts you to some degree
yeah like people are rightfully I mean
if you are literally a victim of
something you're rightfully a victim but
you choose whether to continue on being
like that or not and it's only gonna
attract from your own life if you
constantly just refer to these things in
your life that have been terrible and
you let these anchor you and hold you
back and you just constantly feed into
this is just like a very low ego like
[__] that goes on mm-hmm and people
just use it to stay comfortable like if
they can just come just justify all
their bad actions and all their missed
plays in life because of this one thing
that happened to them mmm Dori that is
never gonna grow like if you never break
the chains of that you're never gonna
you're never gonna feel content or happy
you're just gonna live in this perpetual
cycle of [__] and blame and once you
what I've come to realize that all my
problems are my fault
ultimately they really are and if they
weren't put there by me they still are
my problem
you're the only one who could solve them
we're not solving this and not solving
them as it's pointless like I am the
curator of my own life and to put my
problems on other people is just
unreasonable and not helpful and I will
never get
anywhere because of it so I think
spending time you know granted like just
conversation and gossip is is an
existing thing but spending time
pointing out other people's problems
to know prevail to is like I think
that's a lot of passing the time it's a
lot of what news does to you again is is
is it presents other people's problems
so you have something to talk about with
other people who also have watched those
problems I mean why not talk about your
problems and be like hey man what would
you do for this problem and you could
try that and then you can make your life
better like don't just stay stag and you
know a victim when you're in the victim
mindset it sucks that that word has like
it sparks offended 'no sand it sparks
like I mean offensiveness and and victim
those are both words that have been like
catapulted and stolen by political
whatever but but when you're in the seed
of the victim you you don't see your own
[__] like like in order to get
better you have to stop being a victim
it's kind of like oh okay so so a victim
you know the 12-step program like that
for like getting support soap sober the
first step they always say well we heard
the movies like admitting that you have
a problem well the step right before
admitting you have a problem is
victimhood I don't know that I haven't
studied Tulsa programs I could be just
like it don't let me like ruined 12-step
programs with that but I'm just saying
the the state of being that you're in of
like here's what happened to me and I'm
never gonna get better because of it and
blah blah so in turn you're kind of a
[__] [__] to the people around you
right and it's like when when they're
like hey you got to be nicer to us and
you're like I can't be nicer because
this thing happened well you're in the
victim part and like that's the thing is
what happened to you [__] valid you
know a lot of times these people have
gone through traumatic experiences but
when you're stuck in in the victim spot
you can't move you can't be budged you'd
like well you you would do it too or of
course I'm like this because this
happened and it's like no you are like
this because that's happened but you
need to understand that the only person
who could change it now is you you know
when you're in the seat of the victim
you can't change and improve and move
forward you have to realize that you've
been a victim in that you know with me
with the depression thing
it was like it wasn't you it doesn't
have to be self-imposed to make you know
I finally realized that I was on keeping
myself and depression thinking that I
needed to suffer thinking that this is
just how it is thinking that every
single thought that came up out of thin
air was just me and that's who I am and
all these like evil thoughts and bad
thoughts or just me and the self hate
thoughts are just the only thoughts that
I'm capable of having but you gotta grow
out that victim thing man it'll it'll
it'll keep you down it's it's just not
safe and people living at their whole
lives - yeah I mean you could make a
whole personality out of it how does
that even happen that's people just get
beaten down by the world and the
pressure of life and you just fall in
this perpetual victimhood and you just
go to work Center time come home watch
TV eat and be sad and dude [__] that
when you have that absolutely [__] that
that don't be sad and then your
suffering is also a push onto other
people and I would say that that's not
ethical right like as a person that I
hope cares about other people you would
want to reduce the suffering of others
and if you are internally suffering and
then in turn other people are suffering
because of it you're now way more of a
problem than who thought you were and
that's and don't be upset about that but
it's just something like hey I'm
suffering I'm making other people suffer
and I would like this to not happen
anymore I don't want that dude you don't
want to like you know you don't want to
be mean to the people around you like if
you're if you're if things are causing
you to be mean to the people around you
just I mean listen I don't have to know
you whatever listener if you're being an
[__] to the people around you you
don't want to do that I don't have to
know you at all to know that you don't
want to be doing that do you want to be
happy right like like if you're being
mean and you're being like in the or
your anger or you're lashing out at
people if you don't know how to handle
situations you're screwed
whatever it is that you're going through
because you're in the victim mindset or
if you're stuck in it these things that
happen to you they haven't dealt with
it's like you what's happening is your
intelligence is sabotaging your life you
know like you're turning against
yourself and and just knowing like just
saying that to yourself like now cramp
okay I'm doing nothing I don't want to
be here though and that's all it takes
from there you just you can start
healing you start changing and start not
being the victim to start okay let's see
it see what I can change let's be let's
be aware of my actions my the person
that I am when I show up to to the
people around me my family whatever so
probably I think was about two years ago
I had a very traumatic experience that I
would rather not have documented so I'm
not going to actually talk about the any
of it but it left me with crippling
anxiety and depression and I had never
felt either of those things ever and
they left me with like a lot of like
weird body sensations so I became a
hypochondriac and I just was this
perpetual victim for probably six months
and I completely suffered and I'd never
Intel my outlook and view changed on
life and I decided that if I saw that
was happening and decided to just not be
like that anymore it just was never
gonna change so you can control only
yourself and it is only detracting from
your own life to stay like this and I
really encourage people to not be so
beaten up beaten down by life rather and
maybe just take the steps to not be that
way it will only help you and what hurts
you the most is just remaining this
stagnant pool of sadness and depression
that it's just it feels like you're
drowning and I know that personally but
there is there's air above that if you
just allow yourself to relinquish some
of these things you have to the the air
the god the air after victimhood and
depression and the the colors after all
that the beauty of the world that's
returned to you when you have a such a
change of perspective of like oh okay I
can help myself I mean that's the thing
that that I want to be clear and I want
to like overly explain to people is that
like you can't
you can't remain in the victim place and
get better with with whatever you're
going through I want to go back to what
you just said there is a you know six
months your life where where you had a
lot of anxiety and stuff too you're in
the victim mentality the word victim
again like I said is it's just confusing
nowadays it's it's something that when
you say like oh you're being the victim
it feels like it's like oh yeah that's
offensive that you just said that you
don't understand all these things it's
so can you give me an example of kind of
like maybe a victim but like what's a
conversation that you and I maybe would
have had in within those six months if I
was like trying to say like hey you can
get better by doing this what would your
reaction be as a victim well I thought
so anxiety left me one like like a lot
of bodily tingles and like a lot of
chest pain and whatnot and I was really
convinced that I was just dying mm-hmm
cause I'm like oh and I've always taught
myself like how long this rational
reasonable person like of course I'm not
being melodramatic or I'm not taking
these things to be ridiculous so telling
myself I'm smart rational made all these
feelings more valid and if you would
tell me that hey like yeah you're fine
I'd be like well I mean I do know that
but I'm not like you you don't live my
body you don't know what it's like so
right but I think yeah like you don't
understand these feelings and I
understand them but really what was
happening is you had a misunderstanding
of the own your own feelings yes right
and they're all self perpetuated as well
like I did all this to myself like my
internal workings is the reason I was
here and everyone could see it and even
I could see it on my hardest of hearts
but the irrational because I mean I was
kind of just boiled down to like caveman
instincts chimp brain just like always
in a hyper aroused state just always
anxious always in this fight-or-flight
state and your prefrontal cortex or the
front part of your brain that does all
your like cognitive thinking like oh
you're real thinking shuts off when
you're in fight or flight so it's really
hard to reason so and it's [__] up
saying just know all this stuff and I
did then and it's like you you can be as
rational as you want to but it's very
hard this game
and until I made a conscious effort to
like start meditating and enjoying the
things and just realizing that this is
just the way it this is the way it is
like and I'm just going to enjoy my life
I'm not gonna let this be me because
I've seen other people my life just
become completely wilted right beaten by
things that I don't think are worthy to
be beaten by and I was currently doing
that and I'm like I will not accept this
from my cellphone I live the rest of my
life like this and at one point in time
I really thought I'm like I'm gonna be
like this forever there's never gonna
not be like this and that is the lowest
of low that ever got to just to feel
like I'm just and this is just my life
now and learning to not accept that and
to seek out ways to mitigate these
things I think it all comes down to
mastering the thing between your ears
mm-hmm like your third eye yeah just
kidding but actually a little bit you do
die I think that yeah I think thanks for
sharing that for one it's it's it's so
yeah cuz I got in the middle of it you
don't understand that you can get better
it's you that's gonna do it though yeah
you're really amazed yeah you're deep in
the maze you're like you tripped up yeah
yeah I think a lot of the like genetics
is always a good thing that that happens
to a good good our intelligence like
saying well it's genetics you know like
if your mom had knee problems and your
knee starts to kind of hurt a little bit
you're like oh here it goes here wait
there's the near the knee thing that my
family has a personal trainer limb and
say don't don't [__] succumb to
barley pains just because you think
that's the way it is being in pain is a
failed state you don't have to live like
that so seek out ways to mitigate that
you just don't have to be like that just
because your parents needs her doesn't
mean your f knees have to hurts stop
putting hard labels on everything that's
wrong with you like these all these
things can change for the most part
other than like obviously extreme cases
but even in those things if you come to
terms of that you'll find more inner
peace and just like if you have back
pain don't just except for your back
pain dude like that [__] sucks and you
shouldn't really not accept that I'd see
that that's something that we accept the
victim mentality allows you to accept
what is happening to you like this has
happened to me okay here's another thing
that's happened to me you don't when you
won't get out of that victim mentality
when you watch it out of it you say
here's the thing that happened to me
all right well gotta work a little bit
harder oh okay well the know this this
weight is on my shoulder or well this
weights on my shoulder I gotta keep
doing things though if you don't like a
lesson like that's what I started
looking at all my problems is like this
is just a chance to be better than I am
now
right all right Manuel will touch more
on that the the old body-mind connection
is definite some that I do want to touch
on so on that wonderful note Spencer I
appreciate you and listeners if you're
listening wherever you're at unless
you're in a car because you might just
die stretch right now
whatever you're doing drop and give me
50 but don't actually give me 50 give me
50 seconds of stretching just stretch
your neck tuck your chin to your chest
whether your toes would be your fingers
something we don't do enough is stretch
and I think that everybody should
stretch so don't forget to breathe don't
forget to breathe breathe from your
belly and stretch I love y'all Spencer
loves y'all junk yard love podcast out e